Contactar

www.linkedin.com/in/alexvelezll (LinkedIn) alexvelez.herokuapp.com (Personal)

Aptitudes principales

MongoDB

Prueba unitaria

Java

Honors-Awards

Global Winners at Nasa Space Apps Challenge 2021

First Place at Nasa Space Apps Challenge Guayaquil 2020

Third place in prototyping category at Hackathon DataJam Espol

First place in the category Risk Management at Hackathon Pyweekend 3rd edition

Alex Velez Llaque

GSoC / Software Developer at Shippify

Guayaquil, Guayas, Ecuador

Extracto

I am an Ecuadorian last year Computer Science student. I consider myself a person with ease of learning, passionate when I love something, and have a great commitment and critical thinking on every project I am part of. I strongly believe that all the effort sooner or later has its reward.

I have two years of experience working with web technologies in some startups, both in backend and frontend (web and mobile), and I have done a little bit of DevOps as well. Although I think I have quite an analytical mindset and a passion for algorithms, I think I also have a great passion for visual details.

Among my web hard skills are Angular, React, Vue, hybrid mobile apps with Ionic, I've also set up GitHub Actions and I have worked a little bit with some AWS services like EC2, S3, Lambda functions, Step functions, ECS, AWS LB; and I consider myself a bit good with CSS as well.

On the backend side, I have experience working with Express with databases like MySQL, and MongoDB, and I've also done some projects with Flask.

One of my greatest achievements is that I together with a wonderful group of friends, was among the 10 global winners of the 2021 Nasa Space Apps Challenge, passing several filters from many evaluators from NASA and other 9 space agencies, and being among the 10 best projects out of 4,500+ globally (I still haven't finished assimilating it). Our project was a prototype of a video game to teach children about the dangers that an astronaut can go through on a long journey through space.

Experiencia

Shippify

11 meses

Software Developer

junio de 2022 - Present (3 meses)

Implementing agile methodologies, I was part of the Dash squad, a team responsible for maintaining a core web application for the company. I was commissioned to:

- Implement new features for the web FrontEnd application developed with React using a micro-frontend architecture.
- Implement new features for some REST APIs developed with Express, MySQL, and Elasticsearch.
- Give maintenance and fix bugs of the application reported by users.
- Extract FrontEnd components as Plugins using TDD with React and Jest.

Junior Software Developer febrero de 2022 - junio de 2022 (5 meses)

Guayaquil, Guayas, Ecuador

Junior Software Developer octubre de 2021 - enero de 2022 (4 meses)

Guayaquil, Guayas, Ecuador

Learning Equality
Google Summer of Code Contributor
junio de 2022 - Present (3 meses)

GSoC contributor in charge of improving the accessibility of the Kolibri PDF viewer based on the Mozilla PDF.js open source library.

BioDynamicsTech Desarrollador web abril de 2021 - septiembre de 2021 (6 meses) Guayaquil, Guayas, Ecuador

J 1 / J /

I was comissioned to:

- Improve UI/UX of a mobile application developed with Ionic with Angular.
- Design and implement new functionalities to the mobile application.
- Implement new functionalities to a REST API developed with Express and HarperDB.
- Provide unit testing to some endpoints of the REST API with Jest.

- Provide CI/CD to the REST API using GitHub Actions to be deployed on AWS EC2 machines.

Escuela Superior Politécnica del Litoral 1 año

Desarrollador web febrero de 2021 - abril de 2021 (3 meses)

Guayaquil, Guayas, Ecuador

Full stack developer. I developed an entire gamified mobile/web application and a web dashboard. I was commissioned to:

- Design the data model of the system and implement it using MongoDB.
- Develop a REST API with Express, JWT, and Unit testing using Mocha.
- Design UI for the mobile app using Figma and Photoshop, and Implement it using Ionic with Angular.
- Design UI for the web dashboard using Figma.
- Deploy the web FrontEnd and BackEnd applications to production using Heroku.

Ayudante de docencia mayo de 2020 - febrero de 2021 (10 meses) Guayaquil, Guayas, Ecuador

Teaching assistant of subjects Data Structures and Object Oriented Programming in 1st semester 2020, and of Data Structures and Computer Organization in 2nd semester 2020. I was commissioned to:

- Give reinforcement classes.
- Grade students' assignments and workshops.
- Other tasks that the principal professors assigned me.

Educación

Escuela Superior Politécnica del Litoral Ingeniería, Ciencias de la computación · (2018 - 2022)